Fork the on Githup

KAMEL OUZOUIGH

PHONE: +33 6 74 25 97 45

EMAIL: ouzouighkamel@gmail.com

Socials: \bigstar blog $- \Psi$ twitter - in linkedin $- \Omega$ github

SUMMARY

Kamel is a highly motivated Senior Software Engineer, with 13+ years in developing and architecting enterprise applications. His portfolio ranges from the user interface to middleware, infrastructure and databases

Kamel is intrinsically passioned for high-quality, reliable and maintainable code. He brought passion and dedication to accomplish it.

Kamel is always keen on to learn new technologies, in order to improve his skills and brings new ideas to his job.

Interests: functional-programming oop java testing ci/cd scala microservices architecture

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Groovy, Scala, Javascript, C#, SQL, HTML, CSS

METHODOLOGIES: Scrum, Hexagonal Architecture, TDD, Design Patterns, DDD, CI

Tools: Maven, Jenkins, Sonar, Nexus, Git, Docker, Intellij, NPM, Git

Servers: Tomcat, Glassfish, Wildfly, Apache

OS: Linux(Debian, CentOS), MacOS

DATABASE: PostgreSQL, Oracle, SqlServer

SECURITY: PKI, HTTPS, Cryptography

WORK EXPERIENCE

SINCE MAR 2017 (4 years, 2 months)

Senior Software Engineer at Docusign, Paris

Java Spring Javascript React Wildfly Jenkins DotNet Azure kusto

Design and implement an enterprise application for seal certificates production.

- Setup project(Backend/frontend).
- Created a CI workflow with Jenkins BlueOcean and Docker.
- Created a frontend with React, and Javascript.
- Implemented the backend with Spring Boot.

Design and maintains ID Verfication application - Enabling customers to securely verify signers identities

- Designed and developed user interfaces and core functionalities.
- Integrated with Third party providers with OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect.
- Collaborated with remote teams.

Jul 2015–May 2016 (11 months)

Lead Software Developer at Viseo, Paris

JavaSpringJavascriptGraphiteTomcatMemcachedJenkinsMongoDB

Worked as Lead developer for SFR(a french telecommunications company) on a online shop application for selling internet connection.

(cont. on the next page)

- Improved website speed performance by using an in-memory cache solution (Memcached).
- Maintained and improved application features.
- Automated application release workflow.
- Mentored and helped junior team members.

SEP 2013–MAY 2015 (1 year, 8 months)

Senior Java Developer at Traveldoo, Expedia Group, France

Java DDD GWT Weld Tomcat JPA/Hibernate Intellij

Worked as FullStack developer on an expense management application.

- Refactored legacy code.
- Wrote frontend code with GWT (Google Web Toolkit).
- Implemented an Designed with Domain Driven Design concept.

Oct 2008-Aug 2013

Software Developer at Onyme, Mediatech-cx, Lille

(5 years)

JavaJava EEHibernateJMSJSF2ArquillianSpockPostgreSQLGlassfishSpockjQueryXSLT

Lead developer of an enterprise application for customers feedback solution.

- Architected application with Java EE stack.
- Mentored junior team members.
- Setup code quality metrics and rules with the team.
- Setup continuous integration workflow with Jenkins.

Jan 2007-Jun 2007

Research and Development at **University of Artois**, Engineering and Automation of The Artois (LGI2A).

(5 months)

FICO Xpress AI

Research and Development on Vehicle Routing problem with maintenance costs.

- Developed a model for optimization.
- Reference: https://www.lgi2a.univ-artois.fr/spip/en/directory/gilles-goncalves

Jan 2007–Jun 2007 (6 months)

Research and Development at University of Boumerdes.

Java

Optimizing the preventive maintenance costs by genetic algorithm.

- Research and Development on reliabilities of a complex systems.
- Wrote Genetic Algorithm based on reliability.

EDUCATION

2008 **Master degree in Web Software Engineering** - University of Artois - France

2007 Master degree in Artificial Intelligence - University of Artois - France

2005 **Software Engineer** - University of Boumerdes - Algeria

SKILLS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

LANGUAGES: French, English, Arabic

CERTIFICATION

OCP Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer — Licence OC1071567